Kurt Peters

Web Developer and Digital Design Professional

Wauconda, IL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Kurt-Peters/8e174465d01e8857

Digital design professional experienced in web development, digital / graphic design, and photography. Key strengths include high-end website design / development, advanced technical skills, ability to flourish in fast paced environments, project management, and client services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Groupon - Chicago, IL - June 2011 to Present

Currently using technologies such as node.js, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, and CSS3 to enhance the Groupon web experience.

UX Core / Social Front End Developer (Contractor)

Sears Holdings Corporation - Hoffman Estates, IL - April 2011 to June 2011

Developed UI prototypes for SEARS, Kmart, Kenmore, and SEARS social brands.

Designed the admin UI for Sears Holdings Corporation's circuit

breaker application.

Performed proxy integration for debugging all brands under the

SHC umbrella.

Front End web Developer

CELECT - Evanston, IL - October 2010 to March 2011

Created a site build process which is 75% more time efficient then Celect's current one.

Completed site builds with the use of JavaScript/jQuery, XHTML, PHP, and CSS/SASS.

Worked closely with the design department to establish a better brand for CelectÕs corporate image and CMS platform.

Created best practices for SEO within Celect's site build process.

Built custom Facebook applications and fan pages with Photoshop, PHP, and FBML (Facebook Markup Language).

Maintained DNS control for clients working with the Celect platform.

VP / Creative Development

DIGITAL ROKKET - San Diego, CA - March 2010 to January 2011

Head of both the Design and Development departments.

Manage and develop web interfaces using PHP, JavaScript/iQuery, XHTML, and CSS.

Manage and design high-end web layouts using the Adobe Creative Suite for multiple projects.

Primary graphic designer and project manager for all client advertising materials.

Management of commercial photography projects requiring planning, follow-through, and achieving results that met client objectives.

Responsible for quality control of web standards and cross-browser testing.

Gymnastics Instructor

YMCA - San Diego, CA - April 2009 to August 2010

Coached and supervised classes of up to seven kids.

Taught kids about discipline and dedication through the art of gymnastics.

Creative Director

SOCAL WEB GROUP - San Diego, CA - December 2009 to March 2010

Supervised and managed a team of professional designers to achieve deadlines for projects.

Monitored work progress and managed concerns for client maintenance requests.

Designed and edited web layouts using the Adobe Creative Suite.

Templated web interfaces using JavaScript/jQuery, XHTML, and CSS for development.

Digital Designer / Photographer

SOCAL WEB GROUP - San Diego, CA - October 2009 to December 2009

Planned and designed advertisement materials.

Designed and edited web layouts using the Adobe Creative Suite.

Performed photographic duties such as planning props, equipment usage, and selecting locations with proper lighting.

Intern

TAYLOR & POND - San Diego, CA - February 2009 to July 2009

Complete web updates and SEO improvements for Herbalife and other TP clients.

Design web layouts and modify Flash advertisements using the Adobe software.

Build web interfaces using a tableless CSS format.

Create status reports for clients using Google Analytics and other analytics software.

Assistant Intern

AUDIO VIDEO SUPPLY - San Diego, CA - September 2008 to December 2008

Hand-coded SHTML pages for avsupply.com.

Quality control and updates of the AVS site to meet SEO requirements.

Created promotional online display ads using Adobe software.

Lead Intern - required to take on more responsibilities than a typical intern.

EDUCATION

Digital Design

UCSD DIGITAL ARTS CENTER - San Diego, CA September 2009

Web Design for Graphics Professional Design

ART INSTITUTE OF CALIFORNIA - SAN DIEGO - San Diego, CA January 2009

Web Design & Interactive Media

SAN DIEGO COMMUNITY COLLEGE DISTRICT - San Diego, CA October 2007 to September 2008

SKILLS

Front-End Web Development, Digital Design, and Photography

LINKS

http://kurtpeters.com

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skill Set

HTML5 / XHTML / Jade / HAML - Advanced CSS3 / CSS / Stylus / SASS - Advanced

JavaScript / jQuery / CoffeeScript - Advanced

Adobe Photoshop - Advanced

Adobe Illustrator - Advanced

SEO (search engine optimization) - Advanced

Digital Photography - Advanced

Front End Architecture - Advanced

Ruby on Rails - Intermediate

Node.js - Intermediate

PHP - Intermediate

MySQL - Intermediate

AJAX - Intermediate

XML / RSS / JSON - Intermediate

Git - Intermediate

DNS Control - Intermediate

Analytic Data Integration - Intermediate

Adobe Flash / ActionScript3.0 - Intermediate

Adobe InDesign - Intermediate

Adobe Dreamweaver - Intermediate

Microsoft Office / Google Docs - Intermediate

Illustration (Fine Art) - Intermediate

Drupal - Basic

WordPress - Basic

Joomla! - Basic

Apache Web Server - Basic

Nginx Web Server - Basic

ASP - Basic

Adobe After Effects - Basic

Adobe Bridge - Basic